hey guys so we have a cube right here is
a very nice looking cube to find the
volume of the cube if we call this edge
s then it would be s cubed if you have
another cube larger its volume would
also be s cubed where s is the length of
one of these edges on this blue one if i
make this edge equal to one meter then
the volume would equal one meter cubed
it's literally a cube of dimensions of
one meter now on the red cube if i
double the length of the edge when i
calculate the volume it ends up being
eight times larger so double the edge
volume is eight times larger now let's
look at spheres the formula for the
volume of a sphere is four thirds pi r
cubed if this blue sphere has a radius
equal to approximately 0.62 meters the
volume would be equal to one meter cube
it'd be the same volume as this blue
cube up here and then for the red sphere
if i double the radius then the volume
would be equal to eight meters cubed
double the radius i get eight times the
volume so now let's look at a pizza we
can think of a pizza as a cylinder so
it's volume equals pi r squared h and
let's also look at a larger pizza which
would also be a cylinder i want to make
these very very large pizzas i'm going
to make the height of it about 5
centimeters which would end up being
0.05 i'm plugging that in for h if the
radius of this blue pizza is equal to
2.52 meters the volume of the pizza
would be one meter cubed that is a giant
pizza now if i double the radius to get
5.04 meters what is the volume gonna be
of this pizza well it's equal to four
meters cubed so when i double the radius
i got four times the volume why did i
get eight times the volume for these but
only four times volume for this answer
down below in the comments how exciting